<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Requires Update on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/requires-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Requires Update on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:15:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/requires-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Agilebase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privilege.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-levels&#34;&gt;Privilege levels&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to see data in a table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop&lt;/strong&gt;: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of Agilebase, relating to a table. Namely the ability to&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;modify the structure, i.e. create/delete fields, tabs, change options etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;create, edit and delete views from the table, including creating charts, maps and word clouds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;upload or create printout templates for views&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;view usage statistics about a table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop also allows some extended user features&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;delete any user&amp;rsquo;s comments from a table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;unlock locked records to allow editing (one at a time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;override table options which would normally disallow adding/removing records from a table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow exporting data to a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;import data from spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow global editing of data in the table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privilege levels work in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/&#34;&gt;Learner Progression levels&lt;/a&gt;, for example, only someone at level Citizen Developer level 3 can have Develop privileges assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
