<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Requires Update on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/requires-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Requires Update on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:15:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/requires-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>In Agilebase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privilege.&#xA;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&#xA;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&#xA;Privilege levels View: ability to see data in a table Edit: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options) Develop: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of Agilebase, relating to a table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating user accounts with the API</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Normally, a user account can only be created by a system administrator - see adding a user.&#xA;However there&amp;rsquo;s one special case in which the organisation runs a multi-tenanted Agilebase account. In that case, you can use an API call to create a new tenant in the account and new user(s) for that tenant.&#xA;For example, imagine your organisation is a body for football clubs around the country, where each club was a tenant, i.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
