<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – System Builder</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/system-builder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Builder on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/system-builder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Guide 1 - Build a CRM</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Creating a basic task list</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/tasklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/tasklist/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a Table and associated Views to use it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; User to have watched &amp;ldquo;How to use agileBase&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stage of the guide will introduce you to the basic activities required to build a simple application. We will start by creating a table with different types of fields in order to store a variety of data. We will then show you how to create and control tiles, views and forms which are the interfaces that your users will use to enter and consume this data.
Let us start by building a simple task list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-table-called-tasks&#34;&gt;Create a table called &amp;ldquo;Tasks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our simple application will need to store information about the tasks our users create. This is done by creating a database table. In agileBase this is achieved by navigating to the developer interface and pressing the “add new table button”.
[guide 1 - video 1]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r7nkYcnjyeQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-fields-to-the-tasks-table&#34;&gt;Add fields to the &amp;ldquo;Tasks&amp;rdquo; table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A table of data is nothing without its list of fields. Each field stores a single piece of information. It is simple to add fields to an existing table within agilebase.
Edit the table, type in the name of the field and choose the appropriate type. On creation of the field you will be able to set further options.
For more detail visit - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/&#34;&gt;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following video we add the fields needed to for a simple Task
[guide 1 - video 2]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QgKRVSMM07Y&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-the-form-easier-to-understand-break-it-into-sections&#34;&gt;Make the form easier to understand. Break it into sections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the data structure required to capture a simple task we can think about how it would be used. The user interface within agileBase is controlled by the list of fields and their options. It is a simple task to reorder fields, just use the drag and drop facility when looking at the list of fields.
Use a field of type separator to create sections within the user interface
[guide 1 - video 3]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YwthqTiTroM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now need to provide the user with a way of accessing our “tasks” table and using it!!! This is achieved by a combination of Tiles and Views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info on Tiles - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info on Views - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary:
A view generally provides abbreviated data in the form of a list of records. It also provides the ability to drill through to see the full record details.
Tiles are a way of grouping functionality together. Specifically, a data tile is a way of grouping a collection of views that all share some common theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this guide, we need a tile and collection of views dedicated to helping us create and manage our “Tasks”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-the-table-available-for-use&#34;&gt;Make the table available for use!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-a-tile-to-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Adding a tile to the homepage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The homepage of agilebase is made up of data tiles. We need to create a new tile to hold all the views of our taks data
[guide 1 - video 4]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hA7-VzX_A8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-views-that-show-all-the-tasks-that-have-been-created&#34;&gt;Adding views that show all the tasks that have been created&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide the user access to a list of Task records we need to create a View. To start with we will create a view that will list ALL the data.   &lt;br&gt;
[guide 1 - video 5]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P4FnZIYmAIo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-better-way-of-looking-at-data&#34;&gt;A better way of looking at data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users will be familiar with a card or kanban style interface (such as Trello). Agilebase has a similar style of view that can often be useful.&lt;br&gt;
Within a views “options” tab you can set its interface stylle to be “Cards in Columns”
[guide 1 - video 6]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GN7685gOnQ0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;making-views-for-a-specific-job&#34;&gt;Making views for a specific job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst users can apply their own filters and re-order data in a view, it is often a better user experience if there are dedicated views setup that match a particular job. For this example we want to create a list of all the completed tasks with the most recent at the top of the list.
For more information on applying filters - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&#34;&gt;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&lt;/a&gt;
[guide 1 - video 7]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvlUpjFhxJg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-simple-application-is-complete&#34;&gt;Our simple application is complete!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we can quickly see that we have missed implementing a key feature - collaboration. We should add another field to this table - a comments field!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the comments field and its associated comment feed - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/&#34;&gt;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-a-comments-field-to-a-table&#34;&gt;Add a Comments field to a table!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding new fields to an existing table is no different to when creating from scratch. Simply add via the table edit screen.
Adding collaboration functionality to an agileB\se application is as easy as adding any other field! Just add a field of type Comments as shown in the video below
[guide 1 - video 8 *]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d57CDMWmUW4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For completeness the remainder of this stage of the guide covers removing items and functionality that are no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deleting-views&#34;&gt;Deleting Views&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually you will want to remove unused views in order to reduce clutter and streamline the user experience. To do this go to the Properties and Options tab when editing the view and press Delete view
[guide 1 - video 9 *]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YfCz-9Fjt7g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;delete-fields-and-tables&#34;&gt;Delete Fields and Tables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping the user interface streamlined and uncluttered also includes the removal of unwanted or old data fields.
It is straightforward to delete a field from a table. Either clicking the X icon on the RHS of the list of fields, or use the Remove field button on the fields definition. However, extra care needs to be taken as the field may be in use as the following video demonstrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N.b. to completely remove a table you are first required to delete ALL the fields it contains.
[guide 1 - video 10 *]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ExSypK06W8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before setting up a BI connection, please be aware of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting#privacy-and-data-security&#34;&gt;data privacy and security&lt;/a&gt; considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At agileBase we host an instance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://superset.apache.org&#34;&gt;Apache Superset&lt;/a&gt; which can be used by customers to create reporting dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the setup processes below also applies to third party tools such as Power BI. In fact, any tool which utilises &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Database_Connectivity&#34;&gt;ODBC&lt;/a&gt; can be used, such as Excel for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-setup&#34;&gt;Initial Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; to request we prepare your account. This will also allow connections from Apache Superset, Power BI or any other tool which can connect to ODBC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to use our supplied instance of Superset, we will then set up as many Superset users you require - there is no ongoing cost for these login accounts. Note that Superset logins are separate from agileBase ones - the usernames and passwords can be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use Power BI, then the process is as follows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the PostgreSQL ODBC driver from &lt;a href=&#34;https://odbc.postgresql.org/&#34;&gt;https://odbc.postgresql.org/&lt;/a&gt;. Use the Downloads link and if running on Windows, use the newest driver from the &lt;strong&gt;msi&lt;/strong&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your operating system&amp;rsquo;s control panel to set up the ODBC driver, using the login details we supply. Ensure the SSL mode is set to &amp;lsquo;require&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Power BI, add a connection using the PostgreSQL ODBC driver, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the built-in Power BI PostgreSQL driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sending-data-to-superset-or-power-bi&#34;&gt;Sending data to Superset or Power BI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A developer with MANAGE privileges on a view&amp;rsquo;s parent table can set this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In agileBase, open the view you wish to report on. Ensure it has all the necessary fields and calculations in it which you want to report on. If not, add them before continuing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the charting icon to view the chart setup interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the bottom of the screen, tick &amp;lsquo;send data to a shareable dashboard&amp;rsquo;. As this makes data available &lt;a href=&#34;charting#privacy-and-data-security&#34;&gt;outside of agileBase&lt;/a&gt;, you will be asked to confirm you will treat the data in a way which maintains privacy and security before enabling the feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a few seconds, the data will then be visible to your external application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view set up in this way is free, further views can be purchased in bundles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy for developers to make changes to views in agileBase, for example adding / removing fields, changing calculations or just renaming a view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when the BI connection is active, bear in mind that certain changes could break it. The reason is that once data is set up to transfer to a separate system, the other system typically expects it to remain in the same format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that if you rename the view or move it, or rename/delete fields and calculations, you may afterwards need to check your charts in Superset / Power BI, to see if they need re-creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-updates&#34;&gt;Daily updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the view has been set up, external applications will see a new read-only snapshot of data once a day. If your data needs to be updated more often, you can add a workflow button to accomplish that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the view A is used for reporting only, in particular it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From another view B, edit the view and go to the &amp;lsquo;workflow - edit records&amp;rsquo; panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &amp;lsquo;chain workflow&amp;rsquo;, select the reporting view A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, when a user opens view B, they will see a button at the top of the screen with the button text set to the name of view A. Pressing it will refresh the view A data sent to external applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-dashboards-in-superset&#34;&gt;Creating dashboards in Superset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section applies to Superset only, for Power BI or other instructions please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve set up agileBase to make data available to Superset, you can create charts and dashboards there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &amp;lsquo;dataset&amp;rsquo; in Superset, corresponding to the view you set up above
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the &lt;em&gt;Data&lt;/em&gt; menu at the top, select &lt;em&gt;datasets&lt;/em&gt;, then click the &lt;em&gt;+ dataset&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;Schema&lt;/em&gt;, select your company name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;Table&lt;/em&gt;, select the name of the view that you set up above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;ADD&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom of the dialog (you may need to scroll down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the chart
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Charts&lt;/em&gt; at the top, then &lt;em&gt;+ Chart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the dataset created above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a chart type, then &lt;em&gt;Create New Chart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag metrics (e.g. &amp;lsquo;COUNT&amp;rsquo;) and fields from the left into the appropriate areas in the middle column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Save&lt;/em&gt; and Superset will prompt you to add the chart to a new or existing dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the dashboard from the &lt;em&gt;Dashboards&lt;/em&gt; menu at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on creating charts and editing dashboards, including video walkthroughs, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.preset.io/docs/create-a-chart&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
