<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – Tables</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tables on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Relational Database Concepts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Before diving into the details of building applications, starting with tables, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back and learn some background information about databases, including what a table is. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with these concepts, feel free to skip this section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building back office software with agileBase, a large amount of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing is building database structures, to store user-entered data. agileBase takes care of creating the user interface to allow users to use these structures automatically, e.g. to search for data, add and edit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find many articles explaining relational databases if you look for them on the internet. Most will introduce SQL, the language used to work with databases. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to learn that as agileBase generates it automatically behind the scenes, but the higher level concepts are useful to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a YouTube video with a good introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NvrpuBAMddw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer reading, here are a couple of examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simple-example---what-is-a-relation&#34;&gt;Simple example - what is a relation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine we want a place to store records of suppliers to our business. This could be the start of a supplier management system to compare companies based on quality, accreditation levels and price for example, or to carry out supplier approval processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this we need just one table &amp;lsquo;suppliers&amp;rsquo; which would have fields in such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;company name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a few address fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phone number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just like creating a spreadsheet with column headings across the top for those fields. You can then add a row for each supplier you record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if we communicate with our suppliers, we may want to store the contact details of a few key people at each supplier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, a naive spreadsheet user would add a few more columns (fields in database parlance), things like Contact Name 1, Phone 1, Email 1, Contact Name 2, Phone 2, Email 2. As you can imagine if there are more than one or two contacts, it would become pretty cumbersome and difficult to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our database we can easily do a lot better and create a separate table of contacts that links to the suppliers table - in fact it &lt;strong&gt;relates&lt;/strong&gt; to it. That&amp;rsquo;s why relational databases are so called, just because they&amp;rsquo;re very good at dealing with relations between tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have our contact table, maybe with fields&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct Line number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect them we add another field of a special type, called a &lt;em&gt;relation&lt;/em&gt;. It can be called Company, but rather than storing the company name again (we already have stored the company name in the suppliers table), it will be a link to a particular company. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about how that works behind the scenes, just know that the Company relation links to a supplier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** TODO: diagram **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now add as many contacts as we like to a supplier. And if we decide to store some more data about each contact, maybe a link to their LinkedIn profile for example, we can add that field to the contacts table and it will automatically be there for all contacts (as opposed to our naive spreadsheet example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-more-complex-example&#34;&gt;A more complex example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a good start. Moving on, there&amp;rsquo;s one more type of relation it&amp;rsquo;s useful to understand - the &amp;lsquo;many to many&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our link between contacts and suppliers above is called a &amp;lsquo;one to many&amp;rsquo; (or sometimes many to one) relationship. The reason is simply that one supplier can have many contacts attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if we think about a more complex case? Suppose our suppliers supply us with raw materials, for example ingredients and packaging. We may want to record which materials each supplier supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could set it up as above, where we have a raw materials table. A raw material has a relation field linking it to a supplier, so one supplier can supply many materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what happens if a particular raw material is supplied by more than one company? You may have a primary supplier, then various fallbacks for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d have to create a new raw material record for each supplier. That would be ok if our raw material record consisted of nothing more than a name and maybe a price, but there could be dozens or hundreds of fields added as we build up our system - to store nutritional information, chemical properties, allergens, etc. etc. That would mean lots of duplication to keep track of. And if we want to later build recipes which use our raw materials, we&amp;rsquo;d probably just want a recipe to refer to &amp;lsquo;flour&amp;rsquo;, not &amp;lsquo;flour from Supplier X&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution is to create a &lt;strong&gt;many to many&lt;/strong&gt; relation, where one supplier can provide many raw materials but also a single raw material can be linked to many different suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no new field type to get to know, we just use the standard one to many relation we&amp;rsquo;ve already learned about in a clever new way - we use two of them, plus a join table. The structure looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO: diagram of junction table&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table in the middle, Links, is called a join table, or junction table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a normal relation field linking it to suppliers, and also one linking to ingredients. By adding a record to the links table, we can join any ingredient to any supplier. A supplier can then have lots of ingredients, but an ingredient can also have lots of suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video above also explains this type of relation if you&amp;rsquo;ve not already watched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-to-use-the-many-to-many&#34;&gt;When to use the many to many&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have a niggling thought at the back of your mind: how do I know whether it&amp;rsquo;s best to use a simple one to many relation, or a more complex many to many setup? Surely I could use many to many for contacts and suppliers too? A single contact may be associated with more than one supplier, for example if they&amp;rsquo;re a contractor, or if they move jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to that just comes down to your judgement. Although agileBase creates a friendly, easy to use interface on top of the data structure, the many to many does add complexity. So it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a trade-off. However the advantage of a no-code system like agileBase is that you can rapidly try out ideas and see which one works best. As time goes on you&amp;rsquo;ll get a sense of what works best in which situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to learn more about this topic, it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;database normalisation&amp;rsquo; and there&amp;rsquo;s plenty written about it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that gives you a bit of background about what a table is, what a relation is and how they work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A table is a store of data about a single concept e.g. a company or contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A relation field links tables together e.g. a contact belongs to a company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many to many relations (created with a join table) are sometimes useful. They allow us to link many records of one table to many of another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all of the most important information you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know about data structures. The rest of the documentation will show you how to create applications practically. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Adding and removing</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A table is a store of data of a particular type e.g. a company, contact, product or invoice. Tables are the fundamental building blocks of an agileBase application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-table&#34;&gt;Adding a table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Build Tables&lt;/em&gt; menu in the lefthand sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;create a new table&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom of the list of existing tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If necessary, click the pencil icon in the toolbar to see the details of the table you just created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO: image&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can change the table&amp;rsquo;s name and add a longer description under &lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. This description will be used as help text in the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;naming-tables&#34;&gt;Naming tables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When naming a table, it&amp;rsquo;s best to use a plural form. Also avoid filler endings like &amp;lsquo;info&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;details&amp;rsquo;. So rather than &amp;lsquo;company info&amp;rsquo;, you might call a table &amp;lsquo;companies&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that the user interface will automatically convert plural names into singular forms where appropriate. So for example if there&amp;rsquo;s a plus button on the screen to allow the user to add a new record in the table, it will automatically recognise the table and title the button Add Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you build a large system with lots of tables, you may find it a good idea to prefix table names using a numbering/lettering system e.g.
&lt;code&gt;a) table 1&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;b) table 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the administrator interface, tables are listed alphabetically, so you can arrange the tables into a logical order with this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user interface will strip out any prefixes when displaying names to users, if they end with a closing bracket &lt;code&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-a-table&#34;&gt;Removing a table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before removing a table, you first need to remove all views and fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to remove actual data records from the table first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of existing views is visible in the &lt;em&gt;manage&lt;/em&gt; tab of the table, at the top right. Visit each view and delete it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then next to the table&amp;rsquo;s manage tab is the &lt;em&gt;fields&lt;/em&gt; tab. Delete all the existing fields from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When deleting views and fields, you may find you have to first delete other views or fields they depend on. In complex systems there can be chains of objects that need to be deleted in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deleting is a destructive process so is not highly automated on purpose, to avoid accidental deletion. However at each stage you&amp;rsquo;ll be shown any dependencies which have to be removed first, so you can follow through the chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all views and fields have been deleted, you may need to reload the table by choosing it from the list under &lt;em&gt;Build Tables&lt;/em&gt;. In the &lt;em&gt;manage&lt;/em&gt; tab, the &lt;em&gt;Delete Table&lt;/em&gt; button should now be enabled and you can click it to perform the final step of the deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Table layouts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;For each table, agileBase will automatically build a data entry form for users to view, add and edit records with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layout of this form can be controlled by selecting a layout option and adding separators to create blocks i.e. groups of fields which go together. This will create a more pleasant and usable system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;layout&#34;&gt;Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layout option is the main control. There are three options&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;single column&lt;/strong&gt; - a simple vertical list of fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blocks in two columns&lt;/strong&gt; - makes the best use of screen space for large forms. Also allows tabs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All fields before the first separator are displayed in a section at the top of the screen, in two columns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that, each separator added creates a new block of fields. Blocks are arranged in two &amp;lsquo;newspaper&amp;rsquo; style columns which are displayed below the top section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the table has tabs, they are displayed below the top section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;process flow&lt;/strong&gt; - blocks of fields are arranged vertically one after each other, works well when there the data entry form maps to a set process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what the same data entry form looks like in each of the three configurations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO: image&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and here&amp;rsquo;s an example of &lt;strong&gt;2. blocks in two columns&lt;/strong&gt; with tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO: image&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;separators&#34;&gt;Separators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To form a block, click on the &lt;em&gt;fields&lt;/em&gt; tab of a table and add a field of type &amp;lsquo;separator&amp;rsquo; - see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://todo.com&#34;&gt;fields reference&lt;/a&gt;. Move it to where the start of the block should be i.e. before the first field in the block.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Hierarchy Navigation</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;agileBase does its best with sensible defaults to create a friendly user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s useful for an administrator to know how to configure and tweak the system to allow the to user navigate the structure of an application in the most intuitive way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
