<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tables on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tables on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 09:56:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relational Database Concepts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Before diving into the details of building applications, starting with tables, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back and learn some background information about databases, including what a table is. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with these concepts, feel free to skip this section.&#xA;When building back office software with Agilebase, a large amount of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing is building database structures, to store user-entered data. Agilebase takes care of creating the user interface to allow users to use these structures automatically, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding, editing and removing</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</guid>
      <description>A table is a store of data of a particular type e.g. a company, contact, product or invoice. Tables are the fundamental building blocks of an Agilebase application.&#xA;Using AI to add multiple tables Providing a short text prompt to the AI will let it suggest a suite of tables which will comprise a complete system.&#xA;For example, asking for a &amp;lsquo;Gym Membership system&amp;rsquo; might result in tables for&#xA;membership types members subscriptions payments classes class registrations trainers trainer schedules equipment equipment usage Agilebase will create all of these tables for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table layouts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</guid>
      <description>For each table, Agilebase will automatically build a data entry form for users to view, add and edit records with.&#xA;The layout of this form can be controlled by selecting a layout option and adding separators to create blocks i.e. groups of fields which go together. This will create a more pleasant and usable system.&#xA;Layout The layout option is the main control. There are three options:&#xA;single column - a simple vertical list of fields blocks in two columns - makes the best use of screen space for large forms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensitive data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</guid>
      <description>In a table&amp;rsquo;s privacy and security panel, there are two options which are worth considering if the data is storing commercially sensitive information (plenty of information in most customer systems falls under this category!) or personal information as defined by EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).&#xA;When either option is ticked, two controls appear.&#xA;Notify administrators on export Here you can enter a number. When a user exports more than that number of records at once to spreadsheet, all administrators (users with the administrator privilege) are notified by email.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Integrity Checks</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/data-integrity-checks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/data-integrity-checks/</guid>
      <description>It can be important to ensure that certain rules are followed when data is entered, either manually by a user, by an incoming API request or someone filling in a chaser response.&#xA;When designing applications, just be aware there is sometimes a trade-off between the ideal of data integrity and everyday concerns.&#xA;For example, you may like to force users to always provide an email address for contacts but in a small minority of cases, they may not have that available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/</guid>
      <description>To access these options, edit a table and select &amp;rsquo;tags and options&#39;.&#xA;Allow add If this is ticked (it is by default), users can add records to the table. Anyone with develop privileges on the table can add tables regardless.&#xA;Only from within tab If this is ticked, users can add records but only when accessing this table&amp;rsquo;s form from within a tab of a parent record. This can help ensure that child records are always connected to a parent and aren&amp;rsquo;t created as &amp;lsquo;orphans&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workflow</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/workflow/</guid>
      <description>The workflow panel of a table shows any workflows which act on data in that table. In other words, any workflow that updates records, creates new records in the table, or deletes records from it.&#xA;Additionally, this panel allows you to choose a workflow to run whenever a new record is created, or (less frequently used) whenever a record is opened.&#xA;That can be very useful for setting initial values for fields, where those values may be more complex calculations than just a static default value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles and Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>When editing a table, the Roles and Privileges panel allows privileges to be assigned to a user or role on a table. Please see the privileges page for more details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usage</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</guid>
      <description>This panel shows a list of views that contain data from the table. Any view with data is included, not just those directly created from the table.&#xA;See usage reporting for more info.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
