<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 20:25:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Development Mode</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/</guid>
      <description>As a no-code platform, Agilebase allows you to easily construct (and later de-construct or &amp;lsquo;refactor&amp;rsquo;) and change your software.&#xA;Toggling development mode on and off To get started, you need to toggle from &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; mode to &amp;lsquo;development&amp;rsquo; mode.&#xA;You can do this wherever you are in the system and you will switch to building or developing the item you&amp;rsquo;re looking at. The three main areas this covers are:&#xA;The homepage. Toggling to development mode on the homepage shows an overview of everything in the system - tables, views, tiles, roles and users can all be listed and edited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learner Progression</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/</guid>
      <description>Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s learner progression pathway enables you to transform your career. You can go from a citizen developer to a no-code software architect.&#xA;Citizen developers can create their own applications using no code. Software architects can build complex applications, including powerful workflow features and integrations with other applications.&#xA;To go on this journey requires no technical knowledge. Beginners - &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; - come from a diverse range of non-IT backgrounds. The only skills you need are the ability to think, be willing to learn, and be able to plan.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
