<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hierarchy Navigation on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hierarchy Navigation on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:15:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tabs</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabs are one way of exposing relationships between tables, to allow the user to navigate the structure of an application. For example, in a companies table, a contacts tab may show all the people employed at that particular company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The user interface can display more than two levels of structure on screen in other ways (e.g. showing a menu in a tab) and wherever the user is, they can navigate up or down the hierarchy of data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To grandchild records</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/to-grandchild-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/to-grandchild-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/&#34;&gt;Tabs&lt;/a&gt; allow navigation from a parent record to a child, e.g. an organisation to a contact, order to order line, recipe to ingredient etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, that child record may itself have subsidiary records of its own, e.g. a contact may have a tab for their training records.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When that&amp;rsquo;s the case, Agilebase exposes both tiers of data on screen so the user can jump from the top level, in this example the organisation, directly to a contact&amp;rsquo;s training records.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upwards Navigation</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/upwards-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/upwards-navigation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever a relation field is used in a table, the user has the option to navigate to the related record by clicking a link next to the relation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However its useful to know that if the relation is one of the &lt;strong&gt;first fields&lt;/strong&gt; in the table, i.e. at the top of the form, then it will be treated as having greater importance by the user interface. In this case, the relation will appear as a relation heading, making it clear the &amp;lsquo;parent-child&amp;rsquo; relationship i.e. that one record &amp;lsquo;belongs&amp;rsquo; to another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
