<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security Features on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security Features on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 10:02:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</guid>
      <description>The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, rather than applying them individually. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure how to use roles, a good starting point might be to align them with the job roles in your organisation, or departments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>In Agilebase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privilege.&#xA;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&#xA;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&#xA;Privilege levels View: ability to see data in a table Edit: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options) Develop: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of Agilebase, relating to a table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</guid>
      <description>Exporting to spreadsheet is only one way of getting data out of Agilebase, but it is the most commonly used amongst everyday users. For less ad-hoc data transfers, such as integrations with third party systems involving incoming and/or outgoing data, the API can be used.&#xA;Allowing exports In order for a user to be allowed to export to spreadsheet, a number of critieria have to be matched, to suitably protect your organisation&amp;rsquo;s data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logging in from an app</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s possible for a developer to create a third party application, for example a phone or tablet app, that communicates with Agilebase via the API.&#xA;Now to use the API, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to authenticate as a user, as long as the app has the correct Authorization key(s), it can read and write data to Agilebase.&#xA;However, in some cases the app may need to confirm that someone has a valid Agilebase account before allowing them to use the app.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
