<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Options on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Options on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:45:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/</guid>
      <description>Capitalise field name By default Agilebase displays field names in Title Case. Un-ticking this option disables that, which can be useful for special cases like e.g. &amp;lsquo;pH&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Length (m)&amp;rsquo;, which would otherwise show as &amp;lsquo;PH&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Length (M)&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Icon Rather than displaying a field name, show an icon, chosen from https://fontawesome.com/icons. For example, to show a phone icon for a phone number field, you could enter phone, for an email field envelope or a twitter handle twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/text-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/text-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Colour words When this field is included in a view, highlight it with a colour if the content is one of a number of words. The most up-to-date values to be highlighted are shown in the administrator interface, but as of the latest update of this page, they are&#xA;Text calculations can also be coloured based on the same words - see the calculation options&#xA;Words will also automatically be coloured when a &amp;lsquo;radio button&amp;rsquo; style is used for a field, i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relation Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/relation-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/relation-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Relations between tables are the &amp;lsquo;glue&amp;rsquo; that holds together an application built using Agilebase. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more about this fundamental concept, please check out the relational database concepts page.&#xA;Some of the options for a relation field determine the nature of the links between tables, which can have a great effect on how an app works, so it&amp;rsquo;s very useful to know about them.&#xA;One to one only By default, a relation is a &amp;lsquo;many to one&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Date Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/date-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/date-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Accuracy Whether to record a date as just a year, year and month, year month and day, or with a time: hours, hh:mm, hh:mm:ss.&#xA;Use current time for new records If ticked, set the value of this field to the current time when a record is created&#xA;Date format The format to display in views. Note this doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect data entry screens, which use the browser&amp;rsquo;s standard date picker, which may customise to the user&amp;rsquo;s region.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checkbox Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/checkbox-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/checkbox-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Default value Simply whether the checkbox should default to ticked (true) or un-ticked (false) for new records.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t set last modified Whenever someone edits a record, Agilebase automatically updates the Last Modified and Modified By fields of the table. This option prevents that happening when the checkbox field is ticked or un-ticked. There would not usually be a need for this but it may be useful in a minority of cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Number Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/number-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/number-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Colour outliers Automatically highlight &amp;lsquo;unusual&amp;rsquo; values of this field in views. This can help pick out values which are notable in some way, for example if a number has been entered without a decimal point by mistake (1253 instead of 12.53) or is a statistical outlier.&#xA;Specifically, if the value is more than 4 standard deviations away from the mean, it&amp;rsquo;s strongly highlighted in green (for values greater than the mean) or red (for values less).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/sequence-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/sequence-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Do not auto-populate When this is un-ticked, the next number in the sequence will always be generated and saved for this field, whenever a new record is created.&#xA;When the option is ticked, the field value will be left blank when a new record is created. A button will appear in place of the value, which on pressed will create and save the next sequence value.&#xA;One benefit of this is to allow &amp;lsquo;accidental&amp;rsquo; creation of records without using up the next value in the sequence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separator Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/separator-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/separator-options/</guid>
      <description>A field separator creates a block of fields, starting with the separator and ending at the next one (or the last field in the table).&#xA;These blocks can either be initially contracted, or expanded. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot showing a number of contracted blocks, with one expanded.&#xA;To program the initial state of the block Create a view from the table the separator is in Add filters to that view that leave only records which the block should be expanded in present In the fields tab of the table, click field options and select the view for the expand if record in view option There are two other selections that can be made for the expand if record in view option other than selecting a view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Referenced Data Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Use as a filter for relations See Common build patters - custom filtering when using a relation&#xA;Prominent Make the background of the referenced panel bright red - useful for showing warnings on screen.&#xA;If the referenced field is a workflow button, then it will become mandatory - it will need to be pressed on every visit to a record, if the field is visible&#xA;Display of fields Controls the display style - what content should be included the output, and also the format of the output: a standard panel, or various tabular styles, often used when there&amp;rsquo;s lots of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>File Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/file-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/file-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Type The type of document typically stored by this field. Can be&#xA;Document - such as a PDF file or spreadsheet for example Image/photo Profile photo The selection affects the display in the user interface in some ways. In particular when a profile photo field is moved to the start of the record, it is displayed as part of the record header.&#xA;Image resolution This option allows you to specify that the system should automatically down-size any large images uploaded.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
