<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citizen Developer Level 2 on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citizen Developer Level 2 on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 15:21:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Development Mode</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/</guid>
      <description>As a no-code platform, Agilebase allows you to easily construct (and later de-construct or &amp;lsquo;refactor&amp;rsquo;) and change your software.&#xA;Toggling development mode on and off To get started, you need to toggle from &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; mode to &amp;lsquo;development&amp;rsquo; mode.&#xA;You can do this wherever you are in the system and you will switch to building or developing the item you&amp;rsquo;re looking at. The three main areas this covers are:&#xA;The homepage. Toggling to development mode on the homepage shows an overview of everything in the system - tables, views, tiles, roles and users can all be listed and edited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. Creating a basic task list</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/tasklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/tasklist/</guid>
      <description>Learning Aim: Create a Table and associated Views to use it!&#xA;Prerequisites: User to have watched &amp;ldquo;How to use Agilebase&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Introduction This stage of the guide will introduce you to the basic activities required to build a simple application. We will start by creating a table with different types of fields in order to store a variety of data. We will then show you how to create and control tiles, views and forms which are the interfaces that your users will use to enter and consume this data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relational Database Concepts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Before diving into the details of building applications, starting with tables, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back and learn some background information about databases, including what a table is. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with these concepts, feel free to skip this section.&#xA;When building back office software with Agilebase, a large amount of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing is building database structures, to store user-entered data. Agilebase takes care of creating the user interface to allow users to use these structures automatically, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/</guid>
      <description>A tile on a user&amp;rsquo;s home screen represents an application or module of an application - a collection of data and functionality that forms a coherent whole.&#xA;There are four types of tile, each of which present data in a different way.&#xA;Data tile the most common tile type - from the administrator&amp;rsquo;s viewpoint this is a collection of views. The user can navigate the views, search for data, edit records etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Developer Level 2</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You are now well on your way through the Agilebase journey.&#xA;This level is suggested or &amp;lsquo;unlocked&amp;rsquo; once a citizen developer has carried out a certain number of citizen development functions and has therefore started to learn how no code development works in a safe environment.&#xA;However to activate the level, it must be manually assigned by a Software Architect level user, as it allows changes to the system which can affect other users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. Capturing Company and Contact data (Introducing Relational Databases)</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/adding-relational-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/adding-relational-data/</guid>
      <description>Learning Aim: Create related Tables to demonstrate the power of relational databases&#xA;Prerequisites: User to have watched “Creating a basic task list” video&amp;quot;&#xA;Introduction In this step of the guide we will build the engine of our CRM and in doing so start to introduce the concept of a relational database. We will do this as a practical example and you’ll see how agilebase makes this straight forward. We will be building a bigger system, but for the most part it’s simply reusing things we’ve already covered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tables</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/</guid>
      <description>These pages provide a guide to using tables, which are the backbone of data storage in Agilebase. Agilebase offers rich table functionality so that data can be processed in the optimal way for your application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3. Adding a Sales Pipeline - Kanban</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/sales-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/sales-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Learning Aim: Introduce Kanban / Card view. Power of dropdowns on fields. Show how easy to add graphs. Show off the advanced UI elements of aB&#xA;Prerequisites: User to have watched “Capturing Company and Contact details” video. Understand relational data&#xA;Introduction In this step of our guide we going to look at adding a dropdown field to &amp;ldquo;control&amp;rdquo; data input as we want to set up a Kanban board approach to managing Sales Opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding, editing and removing</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/</guid>
      <description>A table is a store of data of a particular type e.g. a company, contact, product or invoice. Tables are the fundamental building blocks of an Agilebase application.&#xA;Using AI to add multiple tables Providing a short text prompt to the AI will let it suggest a suite of tables which will comprise a complete system.&#xA;For example, asking for a &amp;lsquo;Gym Membership system&amp;rsquo; might result in tables for&#xA;membership types members subscriptions payments classes class registrations trainers trainer schedules equipment equipment usage Agilebase will create all of these tables for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/</guid>
      <description>Adding fields to a table creates a form by which people (and other sources such as the API or workflows) can enter data.&#xA;There are various types of fields and field options which this section will cover.&#xA;Adding fields automatically using AI If you are starting from scratch, Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s AI can propose a set of sensible fields for your table. Each can then be accepted or rejected according to your needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field Types</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/</guid>
      <description>These pages describe the various types of fields it is possible to have in an Agilebase application. It is recommended to begin with the basic field types before moving on to dealing with special field types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table layouts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/</guid>
      <description>For each table, Agilebase will automatically build a data entry form for users to view, add and edit records with.&#xA;The layout of this form can be controlled by selecting a layout option and adding separators to create blocks i.e. groups of fields which go together. This will create a more pleasant and usable system.&#xA;Layout The layout option is the main control. There are three options:&#xA;single column - a simple vertical list of fields blocks in two columns - makes the best use of screen space for large forms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/</guid>
      <description>Along with tables, views are one of the two foundational concepts used when building applications with Agilebase.&#xA;What is a view? In fact, the concept of a view is not unique to Agilebase, it is a core part of any database system, including the PostgreSQL database that Agilebase uses to store, manipulate and report on data.&#xA;Here are some of the advantages a view can offer, as explained by the Wikipedia Article on database views, slightly shortened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/</guid>
      <description>Choosing suitable options helps make the user experience friendly, and extends the capabilities of applications.&#xA;Some options apply to all fields and others are specific to the type.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a view</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/creating-a-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/creating-a-view/</guid>
      <description>In Agilebase, a view &amp;lsquo;belongs to&amp;rsquo; a table. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what that means in more detail below, but for now, just choose a table to show data from to users. In examples on this section of the documentation we&amp;rsquo;ll assume we pick a contacts table.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ll also assume we already have some tables and some tiles.&#xA;To create a view You can create a view from scratch, or clone an existing one then edit it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Field Types</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/basic-field-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/basic-field-types/</guid>
      <description>These are the core types of fields by which data can be entered by users (or other sources such as the API or a workflow).&#xA;Text Text fields are the most commonly used. Depending on field options, text can be entered into a standard data entry control, a large box allowing rich formatting (bold, italic etc.), chosen from a dropdown of options or added as tags.&#xA;Number When adding a number field, select a precision from the dropdown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/text-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/text-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Colour words When this field is included in a view, highlight it with a colour if the content is one of a number of words. The most up-to-date values to be highlighted are shown in the administrator interface, but as of the latest update of this page, they are&#xA;Text calculations can also be coloured based on the same words - see the calculation options&#xA;Words will also automatically be coloured when a &amp;lsquo;radio button&amp;rsquo; style is used for a field, i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joins</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/</guid>
      <description>Without any joins, you can only add fields, filters and calculations (display data in other words), from a view&amp;rsquo;s parent table - the one it was created from. When joins are added to other tables or views, you can also bring in data from any table or view joined to.&#xA;For example, a view based on the contacts table could join to organisations (as long as there is a relation field from contacts to organisations).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabs</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/</guid>
      <description>Tabs are one way of exposing relationships between tables, to allow the user to navigate the structure of an application. For example, in a companies table, a contacts tab may show all the people employed at that particular company.&#xA;The user interface can display more than two levels of structure on screen in other ways (e.g. showing a menu in a tab) and wherever the user is, they can navigate up or down the hierarchy of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To grandchild records</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/to-grandchild-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/to-grandchild-records/</guid>
      <description>Tabs allow navigation from a parent record to a child, e.g. an organisation to a contact, order to order line, recipe to ingredient etc.&#xA;Of course, that child record may itself have subsidiary records of its own, e.g. a contact may have a tab for their training records.&#xA;When that&amp;rsquo;s the case, Agilebase exposes both tiers of data on screen so the user can jump from the top level, in this example the organisation, directly to a contact&amp;rsquo;s training records.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Date Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/date-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/date-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Accuracy Whether to record a date as just a year, year and month, year month and day, or with a time: hours, hh:mm, hh:mm:ss.&#xA;Use current time for new records If ticked, set the value of this field to the current time when a record is created&#xA;Date format The format to display in views. Note this doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect data entry screens, which use the browser&amp;rsquo;s standard date picker, which may customise to the user&amp;rsquo;s region.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separators</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</guid>
      <description>A separator field doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually store any data, but is used as a marker of the start of a block of fields. Create a separator and move it to just before the field which should be the first in a block.&#xA;Depending on the table layout, these blocks will be displayed in different ways, but in all cases will form a distinct group of fields.&#xA;Inline help can be added for separators in the same way as for normal fields, by adding a field description.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upwards Navigation</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/upwards-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/upwards-navigation/</guid>
      <description>Whenever a relation field is used in a table, the user has the option to navigate to the related record by clicking a link next to the relation.&#xA;However its useful to know that if the relation is one of the first fields in the table, i.e. at the top of the form, then it will be treated as having greater importance by the user interface. In this case, the relation will appear as a relation heading, making it clear the &amp;lsquo;parent-child&amp;rsquo; relationship i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checkbox Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/checkbox-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/checkbox-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Default value Simply whether the checkbox should default to ticked (true) or un-ticked (false) for new records.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t set last modified Whenever someone edits a record, Agilebase automatically updates the Last Modified and Modified By fields of the table. This option prevents that happening when the checkbox field is ticked or un-ticked. There would not usually be a need for this but it may be useful in a minority of cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comment Feeds</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</guid>
      <description>Adding a comment feed to a table adds a discussion area to a form, transforming its usefulness.&#xA;Comment feeds in Agilebase are quite a large topic, as one of the most often used features central to the platform. It&amp;rsquo;s common for at least one comment feed to be added to every table in the system, allowing users to collaborate and discuss data wherever they are.&#xA;The ability to discuss and comment on data can be one of the most important mechanisms used to break down silo thinking and help organisations that wish to adopt a more systematic or process orientated view of things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Help</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/adding-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/adding-help/</guid>
      <description>Help for the application you build can be added in at many levels of the user interface&#xA;at the individual field level add the help for each field when adding or editing a field for a block of fields add the help for the separator field marking the start of the block for a table add the help in the name and views panel when editing a table for a tab within a table the help for the tab view is used, falling back to the help for the tab table for a view add the help when creating or editing a view for a tile add the help when creating or editing a tile If help exists for a particular area, a link is generally displayed on screen as a question mark icon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Number Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/number-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/number-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Colour outliers Automatically highlight &amp;lsquo;unusual&amp;rsquo; values of this field in views. This can help pick out values which are notable in some way, for example if a number has been entered without a decimal point by mistake (1253 instead of 12.53) or is a statistical outlier.&#xA;Specifically, if the value is more than 4 standard deviations away from the mean, it&amp;rsquo;s strongly highlighted in green (for values greater than the mean) or red (for values less).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>File fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</guid>
      <description>By default, a file field added to a table will let users upload files.&#xA;When a file field is added to a view, a link to download the file is included.&#xA;Files previews can be displayed in an image/document library tile.&#xA;Version history When a new file is uploaded (or generated), any previous file is kept as a previous version, displayed with a timestamp, for download by users.&#xA;Generating PDF documents If a template is uploaded using the file field options, the file upload button in the user interface will be replaced by a generate button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separator Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/separator-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/separator-options/</guid>
      <description>A field separator creates a block of fields, starting with the separator and ending at the next one (or the last field in the table).&#xA;These blocks can either be initially contracted, or expanded. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot showing a number of contracted blocks, with one expanded.&#xA;To program the initial state of the block Create a view from the table the separator is in Add filters to that view that leave only records which the block should be expanded in present In the fields tab of the table, click field options and select the view for the expand if record in view option There are two other selections that can be made for the expand if record in view option other than selecting a view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Referenced Data Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/</guid>
      <description>Use as a filter for relations See Common build patters - custom filtering when using a relation&#xA;Prominent Make the background of the referenced panel bright red - useful for showing warnings on screen.&#xA;If the referenced field is a workflow button, then it will become mandatory - it will need to be pressed on every visit to a record, if the field is visible&#xA;Display of fields Controls the display style - what content should be included the output, and also the format of the output: a standard panel, or various tabular styles, often used when there&amp;rsquo;s lots of data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
