<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citizen Developer Level 3 on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citizen Developer Level 3 on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:44:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Developer Level 3</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Software Architect (see below) can, at their discretion, assign a citizen developer 3 &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privileges on a table (or tables).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That allows them to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;add &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/&#34;&gt;fields&lt;/a&gt; to those table, excluding referenced fields&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;remove fields that they themselves have added (not others)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;edit the basic properties of any field in those tables, e.g. the list of options in a dropdown box&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, actions not related to having develop privileges on a particular table are&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4. Calculated Datafields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/calculated-datafields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/calculated-datafields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt;   Introduce calculations and basic SQL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; User to have understanding of relational data&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ability to use your existing data to calculate new information will dramatically enhance the user interface, and lead your users to create new data!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this step fo the guide we&amp;rsquo;ll start with something simple, expanding the data we know about Organisations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;calculating-the-number-of-contacts-belonging-to-an-organisation&#34;&gt;Calculating the number of contacts belonging to an Organisation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using the All Organisations view as a starting point, clone it and rename it &amp;ldquo;Organisation - Calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;capitalise-field-name&#34;&gt;Capitalise field name&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default Agilebase displays field names in Title Case. Un-ticking this option disables that, which can be useful for special cases like e.g. &amp;lsquo;pH&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Length (m)&amp;rsquo;, which would otherwise show as &amp;lsquo;PH&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Length (M)&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;Icon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather than displaying a field name, show an icon, chosen from &lt;a href=&#34;https://fontawesome.com/icons&#34;&gt;https://fontawesome.com/icons&lt;/a&gt;. For example, to show a phone icon for a phone number field, you could enter &lt;code&gt;phone&lt;/code&gt;, for an email field &lt;code&gt;envelope&lt;/code&gt; or a twitter handle &lt;code&gt;twitter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide 3.3 - Records: Advanced UI Control</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide3-advanced-usage/records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide3-advanced-usage/records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;records&#34;&gt;Records&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Full record view is the interface that a user uses to update and create data in the underlying source Table.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This User Interface isn’t simply every field shown on the screen. The power of agilebase comes from providing facilities to control how the user interacts with their data. Put another way, by allowing developers to control individual fields, decide when to show them and group them together etc, the job of entering data becomes a pleasant user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5. Cross References and Automations</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/cross-reference-and-automations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/cross-reference-and-automations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt;   Using Cross Reference (Xref) fields in a table definition to display related info. Introduce WorkFlows (Buttons, sending emails, document generation). Being organised by using a naming convention!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; User to have watched “Add a Sales Pipeline” and “Introducing calculated” video. Understand how to create calculations in views.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This part of the guide starts to introduce some more powerful and advanced features of the agileBase system. It looks at how we can give users of our basic CRM some power ups that make it a better user experience. Let’s continue with our Sales Opportunities and introduce the concept of cross referencing data before adding an automated email ‘reminder’ and a button to the user interface…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relation Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/relation-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/relation-field-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Relations between tables are the &amp;lsquo;glue&amp;rsquo; that holds together an application built using Agilebase. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more about this fundamental concept, please check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/&#34;&gt;relational database concepts&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the options for a relation field determine the nature of the links between tables, which can have a great effect on how an app works, so it&amp;rsquo;s very useful to know about them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-to-one-only&#34;&gt;One to one only&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, a relation is a &amp;lsquo;many to one&amp;rsquo;. For example if a relation field in a contacts table links to an organisation, that organisation can have many contacts linked. If an ingredient links to a recipe, that recipe can have many ingredients. One customer can have many orders - examples are numerous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculations</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to add calculations to a view opens up a world of possibilities. Within the confines of the SQL language, there&amp;rsquo;s no limit to what you can do, and those confines contain a pretty large space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the only area of Agilebase which requires some &amp;lsquo;semi-programming&amp;rsquo; to use - using snippets of SQL. However, SQL is a standard, widely popular and the AI is there to help as you get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Field Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/sequence-field-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/sequence-field-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-auto-populate&#34;&gt;Do not auto-populate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When this is un-ticked, the next number in the sequence will always be generated and saved for this field, whenever a new record is created.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the option is ticked, the field value will be left blank when a new record is created. A button will appear in place of the value, which on pressed will create and save the next sequence value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One benefit of this is to allow &amp;lsquo;accidental&amp;rsquo; creation of records without using up the next value in the sequence. So for example, if an &amp;lsquo;invoice number&amp;rsquo; field has this option ticked, creating an invoice and then immediately deleting it won&amp;rsquo;t use up a sequence value, leaving a gap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some options control the interface that a user sees (whether it&amp;rsquo;s displayed in rows and columns, with headings, or as cards in columns for example) and others affect the contents of the view, i.e. which data records it contains.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both types of option are accessed from the view as follows, we&amp;rsquo;ve just split them into the two types in this documentation for easy understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In development mode, open a view (or open a view then toggle development mode on with the toggle switch at the top right of the screen)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Click the big pencil icon at the top left and select &lt;em&gt;properties and options&lt;/em&gt; from the menu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Display Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/display-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/display-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;show-charts-by-default&#34;&gt;Show charts by default&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a user opens this view, immediately show charts rather than data rows&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface---inline-editing&#34;&gt;Interface -&amp;gt; inline editing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this feature is to allow rapid and efficient editing of data when in the list view so there’s no need to drill down into a record to edit and back to the list again after each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some examples of where this might be useful would be when working through a list of milestones to update statuses, or when in a list of stock items to update quantities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behaviour Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/behaviour-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/behaviour-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;group-by-all-non-aggregate-fields&#34;&gt;Group by all non-aggregate fields&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Affects how some calculation aggregates worked - documented in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/#aggregates-of-child-rows&#34;&gt;calculations -&amp;gt; aggregates of child rows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-exports&#34;&gt;Allow exports&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/&#34;&gt;Security And Compliance -&amp;gt; Exporting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;record-limit&#34;&gt;Record limit&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only return the top N rows of data from the view, even if there are more available. This is equivalent to adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/sql-select.html#SQL-LIMIT&#34;&gt;LIMIT clause&lt;/a&gt; in SQL.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;distinct-fields&#34;&gt;Distinct fields&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If many rows in the view have the same values for a particular field, then reduce the number shown to only one row for every distinct (unique) value of that field. The top row is returned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabs</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/special-uses/tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/special-uses/tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where there is &amp;lsquo;child&amp;rsquo; data related to a parent table, e.g. a contact belonging to an organisation, a list of child records can be shown in a tab in the parent record.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A view can specify which records are shown. Perhaps some should be filtered out, like e.g. contacts who no longer work at the organisation - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&#34;&gt;view filters&lt;/a&gt; can accomplish that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fields of the view are what&amp;rsquo;s shown in data rows in the tab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing from spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/importing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/importing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agilebase allows data to be imported from CSV (Comma Separated Variable) files. All popular spreadsheet software can save data in this format.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;develop&lt;/strong&gt; privileges&lt;/a&gt; on a table can import data into it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the tiles interface, load any view created from the table to import into. Scroll to the bottom of the rows and press the cloud import icon, then follow through the prompts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/import-link.png&#34; alt=&#34;import link&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data can be imported in two ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
