<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflows on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflows on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 19:10:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Types of Workflow Actions</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/types-of-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/types-of-actions/</guid>
      <description>Types of Action Actions fall in to two types:&#xA;Those that effect data held within Agilebase tables Those that send data to another system. Alter Data Use the dropdown within the workflow - edit records panel when editing the view to control the action that will be applied to every record in the view. Options are:&#xA;Create record - This will create a new item in the nominated table Update record - This will alter the values of the record.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altering Data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/altering-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/altering-data/</guid>
      <description>The following workflow types alter data within the system&#xA;Create record - This will create a new item in the nominated table Update record - This will alter the values of the record. Lock record - This will apply a record level lock on the item. Delete record - This will totally remove the record. Deleting records is not reversible. Please use with caution.&#xA;Specifying field values to save When creating or editing a record, the fields in the view will populate the new or existing record.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send Data to a third party via API</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-data-to-a-third-party-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-data-to-a-third-party-via-api/</guid>
      <description>When integrating Agilebase with third party systems, the API is really useful. Programmers can use it to send data to websites, to other software such as PowerBI, a Business Intelligence tool, or to external systems such as label/barcode printers for example. The opportunities are endless.&#xA;Agilebase can either ‘push’ data to a third party system, or have the third party system ‘pull’ it out.&#xA;What’s the difference? Simply put, if pulling, a third party system has to regularly ask, or &amp;lsquo;poll&amp;rsquo;, Agilebase whether there’s any new data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send an email</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/</guid>
      <description>Agilebase can be used to send emails. This facility should NOT be used for marketing purposes, rather as a method to notify people about data associated to the system. For marketing emails, there are more appropriate specifically designed third party apps.&#xA;Note: When setting up an email alert, the system needs to know the email address of the recipient. Sometimes this may be very simple, when you always want to send the alert to the same person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send a Chaser email</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/</guid>
      <description>The Chaser email facility is often used to remind people to send information. This facility is a dedicated tool, optimised to this purpose.&#xA;In a nutshell, the system comprises three parts&#xA;checking when something’s due and emailing the person who needs to supply it&#xA;allowing the recipient to easily provide the data by following a link in the email to an online form. Documents can be uploaded and other information filled in</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send to Document Generator</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-document-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-document-generator/</guid>
      <description>Automated bulk document generation Automatically generating PDF documents based on criteria you specify is a powerful feature. For example, if your system tracks exam marks, you may wish to automatically generate a certificate whenever someone passes. Another more common example might be generating invoices for all the work carried out each month.&#xA;Setting up The concept works much like email notifications or syncing events to Google calendar. A view must be set up that contains the records that you want to generate documents for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI workflows</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/ai-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/ai-workflows/</guid>
      <description>Standard workflows are automations that create, update or delete records.&#xA;AI workflows are exactly the same in that regard: a view is created which select the records to act on by filtering.&#xA;The only difference is that a standard workflow to update or create records will use SQL calculations to define the contents of the field values to be saved. For example, if a workflow creates an invoice record, it might define a calculation to save to a VAT amount field as</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
