<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Special Field Types on Agilebase docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special Field Types on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:12:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Separators</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A separator field doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually store any data, but is used as a marker of the start of a block of fields. Create a separator  and move it to just before the field which should be the first in a block.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Depending on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/&#34;&gt;table layout&lt;/a&gt;, these blocks will be displayed in different ways, but in all cases will form a distinct group of fields.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inline help can be added for separators in the same way as for normal fields, by adding a field description. This help text will apply to the whole block of fields created by a separator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comment Feeds</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adding a comment feed to a table adds a discussion area to a form, transforming its usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comment feeds in Agilebase are quite a large topic, as one of the most often used features central to the platform. It&amp;rsquo;s common for at least one comment feed to be added to every table in the system, allowing users to collaborate and discuss data wherever they are.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ability to discuss and comment on data can be one of the most important mechanisms used to break down silo thinking and help organisations that wish to adopt a more systematic or process orientated view of things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Referenced data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most fields in a table allow data entry into that table, but referenced data fields allow data from &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; places to be embedded, specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;views&lt;/a&gt;, created from any table.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, the embedded data can be editable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This can be used for many purposes, such as&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;showing warning or information messages in a form, based on criteria&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;showing calculations, e.g. when editing a recipe, you may want to show the total cost/kg of all ingredients and packaging in that recipe&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;embedding charts, e.g. in the record for a customer, you may want to show the last 12 months of sales data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;allowing quick editing of related data, e.g. after selecting a customer contact for a sales opportunity, allow quick editing of their contact details without having to navigate away from the opportunity record&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some more esoteric uses are also possible&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatically present fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When every &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; is created, a series of fields are automatically added. These aren&amp;rsquo;t displayed in the data entry form of a table, but are available to be added into views.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;id-field&#34;&gt;ID field&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In database parlance, the table&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primary_key&#34;&gt;primary key&lt;/a&gt; - providing a unique ID to identify each record. Values are generated in sequence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agilebase creates and manages primary keys, using them to link related tables together automatically, however it&amp;rsquo;s useful for administrators to understand the concept and implementation. Many platform features depending on including the ID field for a particular table in a view, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/&#34;&gt;referenced fields&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
